<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Litestream! on</title><link>https://litestream.io/</link><description>Recent content in Litestream! on</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-US</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 01 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://litestream.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Blog</title><link>https://litestream.io/blog/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://litestream.io/blog/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Documentation</title><link>https://litestream.io/docs/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://litestream.io/docs/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Getting Started</title><link>https://litestream.io/getting-started/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://litestream.io/getting-started/</guid><description>Overview These tutorials provide a way to get up and running with Litestream quickly. If you&amp;rsquo;re new to Litestream, you should walk through the Replicating a Single Database tutorial first. That will get you running a simple Litestream setup.
If you want to run Litestream in production, you should learn to deploy it as a service by reading the Running as a systemd service tutorial.</description></item><item><title>Install</title><link>https://litestream.io/install/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://litestream.io/install/</guid><description>Overview Most users should install Litestream using prebuilt binaries as they make it easy to get up and running quickly. If a binaries are not available for your operating system or architecture, you&amp;rsquo;ll need to build Litestream from source.
Install on Mac OS X Install on Debian Build from source</description></item><item><title>Reference</title><link>https://litestream.io/reference/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://litestream.io/reference/</guid><description>The Litestream command line provides several subcommands to help you manage replication &amp;amp; recovery of your databases. This reference provides details about the options available and different modes of operation.
Commands The litestream commands are:
litestream databases — Lists databases specified in config file. litestream generations — list available generations for a database. litestream replicate — Runs a server to replicate databases. litestream restore — Recovers database backup from a replica.</description></item></channel></rss>