<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Litestream! on</title><link>https://litestream.io/</link><description>Recent content in Litestream! on</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-US</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 01 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://litestream.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Blog</title><link>https://litestream.io/blog/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://litestream.io/blog/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Documentation</title><link>https://litestream.io/docs/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://litestream.io/docs/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Getting Started</title><link>https://litestream.io/getting-started/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://litestream.io/getting-started/</guid><description>This tutorial will get you up and running with Litestream locally and replicating a SQLite database to Amazon S3. By the end, you&amp;rsquo;ll understand the replicate and restore commands and be able to continuously backup your database. It assumes you&amp;rsquo;re comfortable on the command line.
You should expect to complete this tutorial in about 10 minutes.
Prerequisites Install Litestream &amp;amp; SQLite Before continuing, please install Litestream on your local machine.</description></item><item><title>How it works</title><link>https://litestream.io/how-it-works/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://litestream.io/how-it-works/</guid><description>Litestream is a streaming replication tool for SQLite databases. It runs as a separate background process and continuously copies write-ahead log pages from disk to one or more replicas. This asynchronous replication provides disaster recovery similar to what is available with database servers like Postgres or MySQL.
Understanding the WAL SQLite has a journaling mode called &amp;ldquo;WAL&amp;rdquo; (write-ahead log) which writes database page changes to a separate -wal file first before later copying those pages back into the main database file.</description></item><item><title>How-To Guides</title><link>https://litestream.io/guides/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://litestream.io/guides/</guid><description>Overview These guides provides instructions for running Litesteam in production on different platforms.
Running as a systemd service</description></item><item><title>Install</title><link>https://litestream.io/install/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://litestream.io/install/</guid><description>Overview Most users should install Litestream using prebuilt binaries as they make it easy to get up and running quickly. If a binaries are not available for your operating system or architecture, you&amp;rsquo;ll need to build Litestream from source.
Install on Mac OS X Install on Debian Build from source</description></item><item><title>Reference</title><link>https://litestream.io/reference/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://litestream.io/reference/</guid><description>The Litestream command line provides several subcommands to help you manage replication &amp;amp; recovery of your databases. This reference provides details about the options available and different modes of operation.
Commands The litestream commands are:
litestream databases — Lists databases specified in config file. litestream generations — list available generations for a database. litestream replicate — Runs a server to replicate databases. litestream restore — Recovers database backup from a replica.</description></item></channel></rss>