<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Reference on</title><link>https://litestream.io/reference/</link><description>Recent content in Reference on</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-US</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 01 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://litestream.io/reference/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Configuration File</title><link>https://litestream.io/reference/config/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://litestream.io/reference/config/</guid><description>The YAML configuration file provides a way to list databases and replicas that Litestream should manage. In addition, there are global variables that can be applied to all replicas.
The default path for the configuration file is /etc/litestream.yml.
Global settings AWS credentials If you are using AWS S3 replication, it can be useful to specify your credentials in one place instead of for each replica:
access-key-id:AKIAxxxxxxxxxxxxxxxxsecret-access-key:xxxxxxxxxxxxxxxxxxxxxxxxxxxxxx/xxxxxxxxxMetrics Litestream produces a continuous stream of metrics that are exported as a Prometheus endpoint.</description></item><item><title>Command: databases</title><link>https://litestream.io/reference/databases/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://litestream.io/reference/databases/</guid><description>The databases command lists all databases in the configuration file as well as list their associated replicas.
Usage litestream databases [arguments] Arguments -config PATH Specifies the configuration file. Defaults to /etc/litestream.yml Example This example shows a single database /var/lib/db defined in the configuration file with two replicas named &amp;quot;file&amp;quot; and &amp;quot;s3&amp;quot;:
$ litestream databases path replicas /var/lib/db file,s3</description></item><item><title>Command: generations</title><link>https://litestream.io/reference/generations/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://litestream.io/reference/generations/</guid><description>The generations command lists all generations for a database or replica. It lists stats about their lag behind the primary database and the time range they cover.
Usage List by database This command format finds all generations across all replicas for a database that is specified in the configuration file. The -replica flag can optionally be used to filter by replica name.
litestream generations [arguments] DB_PATH List by replica URL This command format finds all generations for a single replica by using the replica URL.</description></item><item><title>Command: replicate</title><link>https://litestream.io/reference/replicate/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://litestream.io/reference/replicate/</guid><description>The replicate command starts a server to monitor &amp;amp; continuously replicate SQLite databases. You can specify your database &amp;amp; replicas in a configuration file or you can replicate a single database file by specifying its path and its replicas in the command line arguments.
Usage Using a configuration file This command format will read all options from the configuration file. This is the recommended approach for production systems.
litestream replicate [arguments] Replicate a single file This command format sets up replication for a single database file DB_PATH and replicates it to one or more replica URLs.</description></item><item><title>Command: restore</title><link>https://litestream.io/reference/restore/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://litestream.io/reference/restore/</guid><description>The restore command recovers a database from a replica. By default, it attempts to restore the latest data. However, it can also restore databases to a specific point-in-time if it is covered by the WAL time range.
Restoration will only run if the output database file does not exist so you cannot accidentally overwrite your running database.
Usage With a database path This command will restore a database specified in the Litestream configuration file to its original location.</description></item><item><title>Command: snapshots</title><link>https://litestream.io/reference/snapshots/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://litestream.io/reference/snapshots/</guid><description>The snapshots command lists snapshots available for a database or replica.
Usage List by database This command lists all snapshots across all replicas for a database specified in the Litestream configuration file:
litestream snapshots [arguments] DB_PATH List by replica URL This command lists all snapshots for a single replica URL. This approach is useful when you do not have a configuration file.
litestream snapshots [arguments] REPLICA_URL Arguments -config PATH Specifies the configuration file.</description></item><item><title>Command: version</title><link>https://litestream.io/reference/version/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://litestream.io/reference/version/</guid><description>The version command prints the version of the binary.
Usage litestream version</description></item><item><title>Command: wal</title><link>https://litestream.io/reference/wal/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://litestream.io/reference/wal/</guid><description>The wal command lists WAL files available for a database or replica. This command is not typically used in normal usage and is mainly used for debugging.
Usage List by database This command lists all WAL files across all replicas for a database specified in the Litestream configuration file:
litestream wal [arguments] DB_PATH List by replica URL This command lists all WAL files for a single replica URL. This approach is useful when you do not have a configuration file.</description></item></channel></rss>