<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Reference on </title>
    <link>https://litestream.io/reference/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Reference on </description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 01 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://litestream.io/reference/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Configuration File</title>
      <link>https://litestream.io/reference/config/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://litestream.io/reference/config/</guid>
      <description>The YAML configuration file provides a way to list databases and replicas that Litestream should manage. In addition, there are global variables that can be applied to all replicas.&#xA;The default path for the configuration file is /etc/litestream.yml.&#xA;Variable expansion By default, Litestream will perform environment variable expansion within the config file before reading it. Any references to $VAR or ${VAR} formatted variables will be replaced with their environment variable values.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>VFS Extension</title>
      <link>https://litestream.io/reference/vfs/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://litestream.io/reference/vfs/</guid>
      <description>The Litestream VFS provides read-only access to a replicated SQLite database directly from object storage. It registers a VFS named litestream, fetches pages on-demand, and continuously polls the replica for new LTX files. The VFS is built separately from the main litestream binary and requires CGO. Pre-built binaries are available in GitHub releases.&#xA;Build requirements Go 1.24+ with a working CGO toolchain (gcc/clang). Build with the VFS &amp;amp; extension tags using the repository Makefile (handles platform flags): make vfs Manual Linux build: CGO_ENABLED=1 go build -tags &amp;#34;vfs,SQLITE3VFS_LOADABLE_EXT&amp;#34; -buildmode=c-archive -o dist/litestream-vfs.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Prometheus Metrics</title>
      <link>https://litestream.io/reference/metrics/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://litestream.io/reference/metrics/</guid>
      <description>Litestream exposes metrics in Prometheus format for monitoring replication health and performance. Metrics are disabled by default and require enabling the HTTP server.&#xA;Enabling Metrics Add an addr field to your configuration file to enable the metrics endpoint:&#xA;addr: &amp;#34;:9090&amp;#34; Metrics will be available at http://localhost:9090/metrics.&#xA;Database Metrics These metrics track the state and operations of each replicated database. All database metrics include a db label containing the absolute path to the database file.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Command: databases</title>
      <link>https://litestream.io/reference/databases/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://litestream.io/reference/databases/</guid>
      <description>The databases command lists all databases in the configuration file as well as list their associated replicas.&#xA;Usage litestream databases [arguments] Arguments -config PATH Specifies the configuration file. Defaults to /etc/litestream.yml -no-expand-env Disables environment variable expansion in configuration file. Example This example shows a single database /var/lib/db defined in the configuration file with two replicas named &amp;quot;file&amp;quot; and &amp;quot;s3&amp;quot;:&#xA;$ litestream databases path replicas /var/lib/db file,s3 </description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Command: mcp</title>
      <link>https://litestream.io/reference/mcp/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://litestream.io/reference/mcp/</guid>
      <description>The mcp server provides Model Context Protocol integration, allowing AI assistants like Claude, Copilot, Cursor, and others to interact with Litestream databases and replicas through a standardized HTTP API.&#xA;Overview v0.5.0 The Model Context Protocol (MCP) is an open standard that enables AI applications to connect with external systems. Litestream&amp;rsquo;s MCP server exposes tools that allow AI assistants to:&#xA;View database and replica status List generations and snapshots List available transaction log (LTX) files Restore databases to specific points in time Monitor replication health This integration enables natural language interaction with your Litestream deployment, making it easier to inspect backups, troubleshoot issues, and perform restores through conversational AI interfaces.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Command: replicate</title>
      <link>https://litestream.io/reference/replicate/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://litestream.io/reference/replicate/</guid>
      <description>The replicate command starts a server to monitor &amp;amp; continuously replicate SQLite databases. You can specify your database &amp;amp; replica in a configuration file or you can replicate a single database file by specifying its path and its replica in the command line arguments.&#xA;Usage Using a configuration file This command format will read all options from the configuration file. This is the recommended approach for production systems.&#xA;litestream replicate [arguments] Replicate a single file (Command-line mode) This command format sets up replication for a single database file DB_PATH to a single replica URL without a configuration file.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Command: ltx</title>
      <link>https://litestream.io/reference/ltx/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://litestream.io/reference/ltx/</guid>
      <description>v0.5.0 The ltx command lists LTX (Litestream Transaction Log) files available for a database or replica. This command is not typically used in normal usage and is mainly used for debugging.&#xA;Usage List by database This command lists all LTX files across all replicas for a database specified in the Litestream configuration file:&#xA;litestream ltx [arguments] DB_PATH List by replica URL This command lists all LTX files for a single replica URL.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Command: restore</title>
      <link>https://litestream.io/reference/restore/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://litestream.io/reference/restore/</guid>
      <description>The restore command recovers a database from a replica. By default, it attempts to restore the latest data. However, it can also restore databases to a specific point-in-time if it is covered by the WAL time range.&#xA;Restoration will only run if the output database file does not exist so you cannot accidentally overwrite your running database.&#xA;⚠️ **Age Encryption Note**: Age encryption is not available in v0.5.0+. If you are attempting to restore from an Age-encrypted replica created with v0.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Command: version</title>
      <link>https://litestream.io/reference/version/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://litestream.io/reference/version/</guid>
      <description>The version command prints the version of the binary.&#xA;Usage litestream version </description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Command: wal</title>
      <link>https://litestream.io/reference/wal/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://litestream.io/reference/wal/</guid>
      <description>⚠️ The wal command has been deprecated in v0.5.0 and replaced with the ltx command. The wal command lists WAL files available for a database or replica. This command is not typically used in normal usage and is mainly used for debugging.&#xA;For Litestream v0.5.0+, use the ltx command instead.&#xA;Usage List by database This command lists all WAL files across all replicas for a database specified in the Litestream configuration file:</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
