<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>How-To Guides on </title>
    <link>https://litestream.io/guides/</link>
    <description>Recent content in How-To Guides on </description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 01 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://litestream.io/guides/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Running in a Docker container</title>
      <link>https://litestream.io/guides/docker/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://litestream.io/guides/docker/</guid>
      <description>This guide will show you how to run Litestream within a Docker container either as a sidecar or within the same container as your application. You will need a Docker installed on your machine for this guide.&#xA;❗️ The host and container must use the same OS. For example, running SQLite on macOS and running Litestream on Linux will not work as they use different locking mechanisms. Overview Docker is a common tool for deploying applications and Litestream can be easily integrated into your workflow.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Running in a Kubernetes cluster</title>
      <link>https://litestream.io/guides/kubernetes/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://litestream.io/guides/kubernetes/</guid>
      <description>This guide will show you how to run Litestream as a sidecar to your application within Kubernetes using StatefulSets. Setting up &amp;amp; managing Kubernetes is a complex topic that will not be covered here. This guide assumes you are comfortable with Kubernetes and have a running cluster.&#xA;It also assumes you have a replica destination (e.g. S3) for your Litestream data already setup and you are comfortable with basic operations in Litestream.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Running as a Systemd service</title>
      <link>https://litestream.io/guides/systemd/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://litestream.io/guides/systemd/</guid>
      <description>This guide will get you running Litestream as a systemd service on Debian-based operating systems such as Ubuntu. Running as a background service means that Litestream will always run in the background and restart automatically if the server restarts. It assumes you are comfortable with using a command line.&#xA;Prerequisites This guide assumes you have read the Getting Started tutorial already. Please read that to understand the basic operation of Litestream.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Running as a Windows Service</title>
      <link>https://litestream.io/guides/windows/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://litestream.io/guides/windows/</guid>
      <description>This guide will get you running Litestream on the Windows operating system as either a command line tool or as a background Windows Service.&#xA;Prerequisites This guide assumes you have read the Getting Started tutorial already. Please read that to understand the basic operation of Litestream.&#xA;Running as a Windows Service Running Litestream as a Windows Service means that it will run in the background and continuously monitor and replicate your databases.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Directory Watcher</title>
      <link>https://litestream.io/guides/directory-watcher/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://litestream.io/guides/directory-watcher/</guid>
      <description>This guide will show you how to use the directory watcher feature for automatic database discovery. This is useful for multi-tenant applications where databases are dynamically created and removed at runtime.&#xA;v0.5.0 Overview Litestream supports two modes for managing multiple databases in a directory:&#xA;Static directory replication scans a directory at startup and replicates all matching databases. New databases require a restart to be picked up.&#xA;Directory watcher monitors a directory in real-time and automatically starts replication for new databases within seconds.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Global Replica Defaults</title>
      <link>https://litestream.io/guides/global-defaults/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://litestream.io/guides/global-defaults/</guid>
      <description>v0.5.0 Global replica defaults eliminate configuration duplication by allowing you to set default settings at the top level of your configuration file. These defaults are automatically inherited by all replicas while still allowing per-replica overrides.&#xA;Overview When managing multiple databases with Litestream, you often need the same credentials, regions, and timing settings across all replicas. Previously, this required duplicating settings for each database entry. Global defaults solve this by letting you define shared settings once.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Replicating to Amazon S3</title>
      <link>https://litestream.io/guides/s3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://litestream.io/guides/s3/</guid>
      <description>This guide will show you how to use Amazon S3 as a database replica path for Litestream. You will need an Amazon AWS account to complete this guide.&#xA;Setup Create an IAM user You will need to set up a user with programmatic access to work with Amazon S3. From the AWS Console, go to the IAM service. Next, click Users from the left-hand navigation and then click the Create user button.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>AWS SDK v2 Migration</title>
      <link>https://litestream.io/guides/aws-sdk-v2/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://litestream.io/guides/aws-sdk-v2/</guid>
      <description>Litestream v0.5.0 uses AWS SDK for Go v2 for all S3 operations. This upgrade brings improved performance, better reliability, and enhanced configuration options while maintaining full backward compatibility with existing configurations.&#xA;What Changed? The upgrade from AWS SDK v1 to v2 introduces several improvements:&#xA;Connection pooling reduces latency for subsequent requests Adaptive retry mode with up to 10 attempts for better resilience CRC32 checksum validation ensures data integrity automatically Modern credential chain with improved IAM role support 24-hour HTTP timeout for long-running operations on large databases Configurable multipart uploads for better upload performance Backward Compatibility All existing Litestream configurations continue to work without modification.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Replicating to Alibaba Cloud OSS</title>
      <link>https://litestream.io/guides/alibaba-oss/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://litestream.io/guides/alibaba-oss/</guid>
      <description>v0.5.0 This guide will show you how to use Litestream&amp;rsquo;s native Alibaba Cloud OSS support to replicate your database. You will need an Alibaba Cloud account to complete this guide.&#xA;Setup Create a bucket In the OSS Console, click the &amp;ldquo;Create Bucket&amp;rdquo; button. Enter a unique bucket name and select your preferred region (e.g., cn-hangzhou, us-west-1). Remember your bucket name and region as you&amp;rsquo;ll need those later.&#xA;Create access credentials From the RAM Console, navigate to &amp;ldquo;AccessKey Management&amp;rdquo; under your account.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>S3 Advanced Configuration</title>
      <link>https://litestream.io/guides/s3-advanced/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://litestream.io/guides/s3-advanced/</guid>
      <description>This guide covers advanced S3 configuration options for tuning multipart upload performance. These settings control how Litestream uploads data to S3 and S3-compatible storage services.&#xA;v0.5.0 Part size and concurrency configuration options were added in Litestream v0.5.0.&#xA;Overview When Litestream uploads files to S3, it uses multipart uploads for efficient data transfer. Two key settings control this behavior:&#xA;Part Size: The size of each chunk uploaded to S3 Concurrency: The number of parts uploaded simultaneously Understanding these settings helps you optimize performance for your specific network conditions, storage provider, and resource constraints.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>VFS Read Replicas</title>
      <link>https://litestream.io/guides/vfs/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://litestream.io/guides/vfs/</guid>
      <description>Litestream&amp;rsquo;s Virtual File System (VFS) lets you read a replicated database directly from object storage without restoring it to local disk first. Queries fetch pages on-demand, cache them locally, and stay in sync by polling for new LTX files.&#xA;⚠️ The VFS is read-only and requires CGO. Pre-built binaries are available in [GitHub releases](https://github.com/benbjohnson/litestream/releases), or build from source with the `-tags vfs` build tag. When to use the VFS Serve read-only workloads from a remote replica (analytics, dashboards, reporting).</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>VFS Write Mode</title>
      <link>https://litestream.io/guides/vfs-write-mode/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://litestream.io/guides/vfs-write-mode/</guid>
      <description>VFS write mode enables remote-first SQLite databases where writes sync back to object storage. Instead of the default read-only behavior, write mode buffers changes locally and periodically pushes them as new LTX files to the replica.&#xA;⚠️ Write mode assumes a single writer. Multiple concurrent writers will trigger conflict detection. Use distributed locking or application-level coordination if your workload requires concurrent writes from multiple processes. When to use write mode Edge deployments where local disk is ephemeral but you need write capability.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Using Litestream as a Go Library</title>
      <link>https://litestream.io/guides/go-library/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://litestream.io/guides/go-library/</guid>
      <description>Litestream can be embedded directly into your Go application as a library, giving you programmatic control over database replication without running a separate process. This approach is useful when you need tighter integration with your application lifecycle or want to customize replication behavior.&#xA;⚠️ The Litestream library API is not considered stable and may change between versions. The CLI interface is recommended for production use cases where API stability is important.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>VFS Hydration</title>
      <link>https://litestream.io/guides/vfs-hydration/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://litestream.io/guides/vfs-hydration/</guid>
      <description>VFS hydration restores the entire database to a local file in the background while the VFS continues serving reads from the cache and remote storage. Once hydration completes, all reads are served from the local file, eliminating remote fetch latency entirely.&#xA;When to use hydration Read-heavy workloads where remote latency impacts performance. Large databases where the cache cannot hold the full working set. Latency-sensitive applications that need local-disk performance after startup.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Replicating to S3-Compatible Services</title>
      <link>https://litestream.io/guides/s3-compatible/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://litestream.io/guides/s3-compatible/</guid>
      <description>This guide covers how to use Litestream with S3-compatible storage providers beyond Amazon S3. Many cloud providers and self-hosted solutions implement the S3 API, allowing you to use Litestream&amp;rsquo;s S3 replica type with minimal configuration changes.&#xA;Automatic Provider Detection New in v0.5.0: Litestream automatically detects S3-compatible providers based on the endpoint URL and configures the appropriate settings. This eliminates the need to manually specify options like force-path-style or sign-payload for most providers.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Replicating to Azure Blob Storage</title>
      <link>https://litestream.io/guides/azure/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://litestream.io/guides/azure/</guid>
      <description>This guide will show you how to use Litestream to replicate to an Azure Blob Storage container. You will need an Azure account and to complete this guide.&#xA;Setup Create a container In the Azure Portal, use the top search bar to navigate to &amp;ldquo;Storage Accounts&amp;rdquo;. If you do not have a storage account, click the &amp;ldquo;New&amp;rdquo; button, enter your storage account name, and click &amp;ldquo;Review + create&amp;rdquo;.&#xA;Once you have a storage account, select it from the list of accounts and navigate to the Containers subsection.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Replicating to Backblaze B2</title>
      <link>https://litestream.io/guides/backblaze/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://litestream.io/guides/backblaze/</guid>
      <description>This guide will show you how to use Backblaze B2 as a database replica path for Litestream.&#xA;Create a bucket To begin, you&amp;rsquo;ll need a bucket to store your data. If you don&amp;rsquo;t already have one set up in Backblaze, follow the steps below:&#xA;From your Backblaze dashboard, go to My Account &amp;gt; Buckets Click &amp;ldquo;Create a Bucket&amp;rdquo; Enter a unique name for &amp;ldquo;Bucket Unique Name&amp;rdquo; and leave the remaining fields as their defaults.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Replicating to Scaleway Object Storage</title>
      <link>https://litestream.io/guides/scaleway/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Nov 2021 19:20:59 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://litestream.io/guides/scaleway/</guid>
      <description>This guide will show you how to use Scaleway Object Storage as a database replica path for Litestream. You will need a Scaleway account to complete this guide.&#xA;Setup Create a bucket In the Scaleway Console, click on the green &amp;ldquo;Create&amp;rdquo; button in the top navigation and choose &amp;ldquo;Object Storage Bucket&amp;rdquo;.&#xA;On the &amp;ldquo;Create a bucket&amp;rdquo; screen, you&amp;rsquo;ll need to choose a region and name your space a globally unique name.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Replicating to DigitalOcean Spaces</title>
      <link>https://litestream.io/guides/digitalocean/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://litestream.io/guides/digitalocean/</guid>
      <description>This guide will show you how to use DigitalOcean Spaces as a database replica path for Litestream. You will need a DigitalOcean account to complete this guide.&#xA;Setup Create a space In the DigitalOcean Console, click on the green &amp;ldquo;Create&amp;rdquo; button in the top navigation and choose &amp;ldquo;Spaces&amp;rdquo;. You may need to enable spaces on your account if you have not already.&#xA;On the &amp;ldquo;Create a Space&amp;rdquo; screen, you&amp;rsquo;ll need to choose a region and name your space a globally unique name.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Replicating to Tigris (Fly.io)</title>
      <link>https://litestream.io/guides/tigris/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://litestream.io/guides/tigris/</guid>
      <description>This guide will show you how to use Tigris as a database replica path for Litestream. Tigris is Fly.io&amp;rsquo;s globally distributed S3-compatible object storage. You will need a Fly.io account to complete this guide.&#xA;v0.5.0 Litestream automatically detects Tigris endpoints, configures the required settings, and enables strong consistency for you.&#xA;Setup Install the Fly CLI If you haven&amp;rsquo;t already, install the Fly CLI by following the installation instructions. Once installed, authenticate with your account:</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Replicating to Google Cloud Storage</title>
      <link>https://litestream.io/guides/gcs/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://litestream.io/guides/gcs/</guid>
      <description>This guide will show you how to use Litestream to replicate to a Google Cloud Storage bucket. You will need a Google Cloud account and to complete this guide.&#xA;Setup Create a bucket In the GCP Console, use the top search bar to navigate to &amp;ldquo;Cloud Storage&amp;rdquo;. You may need to enable storage and billing if you have not previously set it up.&#xA;Next, click the &amp;ldquo;Create Bucket&amp;rdquo; button. Enter a globally unique bucket name and click the &amp;ldquo;Create&amp;rdquo; button.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Replicating to Linode Object Storage</title>
      <link>https://litestream.io/guides/linode/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://litestream.io/guides/linode/</guid>
      <description>This guide will show you how to use Linode Object Storage as a database replica path for Litestream. You will need a Linode account to complete this guide.&#xA;Setup Create a bucket In the Linode Console, click on &amp;ldquo;Object Storage&amp;rdquo; from the navigation and click the &amp;ldquo;Create Bucket&amp;rdquo; button. You may need to enable Object Storage on your account if you have not already.&#xA;Enter a globally unique name for your bucket and choose a region.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Replicating to an SFTP Server</title>
      <link>https://litestream.io/guides/sftp/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://litestream.io/guides/sftp/</guid>
      <description>This guide will show you how to use Litestream to replicate to a remote SFTP server. You will need to have an SFTP server already set up and running.&#xA;Usage Command line usage You can specify your SFTP replica using a replica URL on the command line. For example, you can replicate a database to an SFTP server with the following command. Replace the placeholders with your username, password, server, &amp;amp; path.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Replicating to a Local File Path</title>
      <link>https://litestream.io/guides/file/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://litestream.io/guides/file/</guid>
      <description>This guide will show you how to use Litestream to replicate your SQLite database to another file on your local filesystem. File-based replication is useful for:&#xA;Creating local backups on a separate disk or partition Testing Litestream before setting up cloud storage Replicating to network-attached storage (NAS) Development and debugging workflows Usage Command line usage You can replicate to a local file path from the command line by specifying both the source database and the destination URL using the file:// scheme:</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Replicating to NATS JetStream</title>
      <link>https://litestream.io/guides/nats/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://litestream.io/guides/nats/</guid>
      <description>This guide will show you how to use NATS JetStream Object Store as a replica destination for Litestream. You will need a NATS server with JetStream enabled to complete this guide.&#xA;Setup Install NATS Server Using Docker:&#xA;# Run NATS server with JetStream enabled docker run -d --name nats-server \ -p 4222:4222 \ nats:alpine \ -js Using Binary:&#xA;# Download and install NATS server curl -L https://github.com/nats-io/nats-server/releases/latest/download/nats-server-v2.10.7-linux-amd64.zip -o nats-server.zip unzip nats-server.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Replicating Directories</title>
      <link>https://litestream.io/guides/directory/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://litestream.io/guides/directory/</guid>
      <description>This guide will show you how to use Litestream to replicate entire directories of SQLite databases. Directory replication is useful for:&#xA;Multi-tenant applications where each tenant has their own database Applications managing multiple SQLite databases Batch replication without listing each database individually v0.5.0 Configuration Directory replication uses the dir field instead of path in your database configuration. Litestream will scan the directory and replicate all matching SQLite databases.&#xA;dbs: - dir: /var/lib/tenants pattern: &amp;#34;*.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Replicating to a WebDAV Server</title>
      <link>https://litestream.io/guides/webdav/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://litestream.io/guides/webdav/</guid>
      <description>This guide will show you how to use Litestream to replicate to a remote WebDAV server. WebDAV is a widely-supported protocol that allows you to store backups on services like Nextcloud, ownCloud, or any RFC 4918 compliant WebDAV server.&#xA;Usage Command line usage You can specify your WebDAV replica using a replica URL on the command line. For example, you can replicate a database to a WebDAV server with the following command.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>WAL Truncate Threshold Configuration</title>
      <link>https://litestream.io/guides/wal-truncate-threshold/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://litestream.io/guides/wal-truncate-threshold/</guid>
      <description>This guide explains Litestream&amp;rsquo;s 3-tier checkpoint strategy and how to configure WAL truncate thresholds to prevent write blocking while managing disk space. Understanding these settings is critical for production deployments, especially applications with long-lived read transactions.&#xA;Background SQLite&amp;rsquo;s WAL (write-ahead log) grows as database pages are modified. To prevent unbounded growth, the WAL must be periodically truncated through checkpointing. However, aggressive checkpointing can block database writes when read transactions are active.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
